[
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nmain() { int i = 1; i = i + 2 * i++; printf(\"%d\", i); }",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "5",
      "6",
      "7"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "6",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.1258848748019692"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nmain() { #define scanf \"%s is string\" printf(scanf, scanf); }",
    "options": [
      "%s is string %s is string",
      "scanf scanf",
      "%s is string scanf",
      "Error"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "%s is string scanf",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.2942324789487838"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code snippet?\nint a[3][4] = {{1, 2,}, {4, 8, 15}}; printf(\"%d\", a[2][0]);",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "2",
      "0",
      "not defined"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "0",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.31095911792384023"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the output of the following code if x=1234 is passed to the function display?\nvoid display(int x) { if (x != 0) { display(x / 16); putchar(\"0123456789ABCDEF\"[x % 16]); } }",
    "options": [
      "1234",
      "4321",
      "4D2",
      "It will not compile"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "4D2",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.09708918448269688"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum number of times the do-while loop is executed?",
    "options": [
      "0",
      "1",
      "2",
      "cannot be predicted"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "1",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.0814520435450512"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which expression yields the correct value for the expression 1/3?",
    "options": [
      "1./3",
      "(float)1/3",
      "options a and b",
      "float(1/3)"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "options a and b",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.9615673991677147"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the associativity of the ++ operator?",
    "options": [
      "right to left",
      "left to right",
      "a for arithmetic expression and b for pointer expression",
      "a for pointer expression and b for arithmetic expression"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "right to left",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.4025568393968457"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint x=2, y=6; printf(\"%d\", x=y);",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "6",
      "0",
      "1"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "6",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.3784874611309701"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint i = 0; while(i < 10) { if(i == 5) { continue; } printf(\"%d \", i); i++; }",
    "options": [
      "0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9",
      "0 1 2 3 4",
      "0 1 2 3 4 5... (infinite loop)",
      "Error"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "0 1 2 3 4 5... (infinite loop)",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.5672697531152704"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint i = 0; switch(i) { case 0: i++; case 1: i++; case 2: i++; } printf(\"%d\", i);",
    "options": [
      "0",
      "1",
      "2",
      "3"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.8351961542267097"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint ones, twos, threes, others; int c; ones = twos = threes = others = 0; while ((c = getchar()) != '\\n') { switch(c) { case '1': ones++; case '2': twos++; case '3': threes++; default: others++; } } printf(\"%d\", ones); If the input is 1alble, what is the output?",
    "options": [
      "15",
      "34",
      "33",
      "31"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "31",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.14199249478089304"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nmain() { int x = 5; int i = x++; printf(\"%d\", i); }",
    "options": [
      "4",
      "5",
      "6",
      "7"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "5",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.5559638141515442"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint ch = 'A'; while (ch <= 'F') { switch(ch) { case 'A': case 'B': case 'C': case 'D': ch++; continue; case 'E': ch++; break; } putchar(ch); }",
    "options": [
      "ABCDEF",
      "EFG",
      "FG",
      "Error"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "FG",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.781436250556651"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the valid compound assignment operator.",
    "options": [
      "<-",
      ">>=",
      "<--",
      ">>"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": ">>=",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.9016503843253956"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bitwise OR operator is used to",
    "options": [
      "set the desired bits to 1",
      "multiply the numbers",
      "divide the numbers",
      "mask the bits"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "set the desired bits to 1",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.06314364027004626"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint i = 20; printf(\"%x\", i);",
    "options": [
      "x14",
      "14",
      "20",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "14",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.18982067375714706"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint i; for(i=0; i<10; i++) { printf(\"%d\", i); }",
    "options": [
      "0123456789",
      "12345678910",
      "012345678910",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "0123456789",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.6637355616345855"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code snippet?\nmain() { int ones, twos; ones = twos = 0; for (int i = 0; i < 20; i++) { switch (i % 5) { case 0: ones++; case 1: twos++; } } printf(\"%d, %d\", ones, twos); }",
    "options": [
      "0, 5, 9, 13, 17",
      "5, 9, 13, 17",
      "12, 17, 22",
      "16, 21"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "16, 21",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.430872913099676"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint x = 5; x = x + 2 * x--; printf(\"%d\", x);",
    "options": [
      "15",
      "14",
      "13",
      "12"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "15",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.3813882647190747"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?\nint x = 5; printf(\"%d\", x>>1);",
    "options": [
      "10",
      "5",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "id": "2025-08-16T18:23:18.198Z0.7388014433910695"
  }
]